Lowell Thomas Film Collection
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
- 6. Danger Island, 1945-1958; 177 cans
  - 6699 - B Odyssey Reel 16, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2783)
    Possibly set on a naval ship; a large area filled with multiple rockets held up by cranes; men examining rockets; people dressed up in costumes putting on a show with others gathering to watch; multiple men holding some sort of sheet; man getting a haircut while blindfolded; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1957; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2784)
    Medium shot of man in hat, clapboard, shot of man's feet, tribal dancing-men and women, man in hat and suit wearing boa holding microphone in front of stage with tribal dancing and drums, close up of woman hula dancing, close up of feet dancing; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2785)
    two men looking at some piece of technology, fixing wires in a big metal tube, man standing next to equipment, Navy helicopter out on the Navy boat on the water, helicopter taking off from boat, Navy helicopter next to tower, tower with wires connecting to it, men standing next to helicopter, man getting into helicopter, side profile shot of helicopter, side profile of man, man talking on the phone, man looking up at the sky, men working with machines, man sipping from a mug, two men looking up at the sky, men at the railing of the boat; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2786)
    Set on naval ship; man painting "Sue Hawkins" on one of the rockets; another rocket has "Take Me to Your Leader" painted on it; plane reads "Navy" on the side; helicopter flying; another rocket says "Sadie Thompson"; men standing on a tower to reach rockets; another rocket says "Bloody Mary" and another says "Tandelayo"; large crowd of people watching something.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island Blow Up Sun Flash, 1957; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2787)
    The End, trees, large sprays, class three flare starts lower left, flagellant motion, large sunspot and plage, tongue-like flare, large scale disk movies 1/2 angstrom H-Alpha filter, 22 November 1956, 11 September 1956, spectacular loops strong CA XV at their tops, note smooth un-knotted flow left 5 August 1956, 10 September 1956, downward motion in vertical filamentary structure, giant complex loops 28 June 1957, 24 June 1956, limb flare and spray 10 February 1956, large hedgerow ascends next day 29 September 1956, 1 September 1956, large ascending prominences; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Danger Island FX, 1958; 654 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2788)
    Lowell Thomas pointing to places on a map. Shots of nature. Tribal men on boat catching hippo. They get on shore and attempt to pull hippo along with them. Shots of people in village doing different things such as making nets and bathing. Man drawing snake. Two tribal kids bring him a box. Man takes out snake and allows tribal boy to hold it. Boy pokes snake in cage with a stick. Man releases snake onto tree to let boy re-catch it.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Black & White; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2789)
    men in a helicopter, palm trees next to a hut, helicopter landing on beach, man walking by hut, people standing by hut, three men fixing a machine, man leaning on a machine; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey-Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2790)
    Groups of people walking in lines, group of women holding hands, people standing outside little building, group of people sitting down watching 2 women, cranes on back of boat, people working on boat, people standing in a circle holding hands, people dancing?, people sitting and talking, large group of kids, boat, people on boat; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2791)
    Man looking around, soldier?, older man with hat on, moon?, group of men singing and playing guitar, 3 people listening to the music, clapboard, someone holding something in the air, people scuba diving, people in a tank-like truck, man relaxing in a chair, a house/shelter, people standing outside the house, 2 people talking, someone sunbathing; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger island Fiji ISL, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2792)
    Person sitting in front of navy helicopter, navy helicopter flying, men sitting in a boat, box that says "fragile handle with care high altitude observatory Boulder Colorado, 2 people talking and man holding his glasses, man with a hat, someone walking down the stairs and a man climbing over the railing, 3 men looking over edge of railing, body of water, man siting, man playing guitar for crowd; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2793)
    Close up of man; man crouching down and holding something with wires coming out of it; view from plane of city in a valley surrounded by mountains; close up of man and boy; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2794)
    Stilted small house, man looking down, man sucking on something, person with flower in their hair; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2795)
    Two men sitting in a Navy helicopter; trees; men standing by some kind of machine; men raising flags (American, New Zealand) with palm trees around them; military tank; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Fiji Islands, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2796)
    close up shot of man with hat on, side profile shot of man with captain hat on, three men shaking hands, men standing in front of airplane, "Clipper Argonaut" written on plane, railing in front of plants in front of building, man with glasses and hat and paisley shirt on, close up shot of woman, close up shot of man with hat and tattoos, back of man's head, people standing in a group next to a hut, man walking and riding on a bike, man standing next to the shore and palm trees, men standing next to shoreline by boat, close up shot of man, people sitting on boat on water, close up of person eating something, man steering the boat, kids eating on the boat, man working at an audio machine, helicopter by shore of beach, canoe up on the beach; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Fiji Islands, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2797)
    two man in between wire rail, two men looking down at camera, front of ship on water, ship coming up to the shore, looking down on ship from helicopter, island covered with palm trees, man standing in front of hut, group of women standing in rows wearing flower crowns, hut, close up of woman wearing flower crowns, men standing next to a pile of bananas, man cooking, people bringing supplies into a tent, people leaning on a rail, two boats on water, boats coming off of shore; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2798)
    Solar Eclipse; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2799)
    Men sitting on the ground watching people who are standing, clapboard, men dancing?, palm trees, man holding large shell, man looking up, large group of people sitting on the ground, people walking around outside a hut, man standing in shorts/bathing suit/towel?; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2800)
    People gathered under a pavilion, palm trees, tribal people dancing outside pavilion, boys sitting under pavilion, man dancing, others joining, ladder leaning against the pavilion, one man climbing it, man now on the roof, close up of guy with curly hair wearing a visor and a flower in his hair, some people under the pavilion, a pier leading to the ocean, man walking towards the pier, walks back to pavilion, 2 native women and a man making something/cooking, man and a woman smiling with children, close up of man and boy, close up of woman, group sitting under palm trees, ocean behind them, tribal dancing, man in a strange helmet and white skirt holding a stick, more dancing, others standing around, everyone going back to the pavilion.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2801)
    View of village through trees; sun or moon; man wearing grass necklace and people sitting on the ground watching him, possibly a ceremony; kids running around; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2802)
    palm trees, a puppy on a palm frond, puppies on palm fronds, people canoeing on the ocean waves, the ocean, kids bringing in a canoe, man swimming in the water, woman kissing her baby; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2803)
    beach shore, ship in the far distance, fog over ocean, ocean waves, fog, people wearing leis and sarongs, people in leis sitting in rows, people in leis dancing; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island - Eclipse. Eastern Effects, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2804)
    one sole hole in the middle of the screen, tower in the fog over the ocean, credits, "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" screen, Navy helicopter, blond woman with lipstick on; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island trailer, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2805)
    Lowell Thomas in a suit looking into the camera; Format: 35mm; Picture: Black & White; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Danger Island Trailer, 50 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2806)
    Lowell Thomas inviting people to sail the South Sea on an expedition that includes the U.S Navy, Polynesian girls, a group of scientist, the moon etc... on Monday night January 19.; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Optical; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2807)
    men sitting around table outside at campsite, close up of man at table holding unidentified object, shipwreck, shot of ocean, ship sailing through ocean, cargo on ship, men waling on ship deck, meters on ship, shot of foot, man steering boat, aerial shot of island; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2808)
    close up of man wearing mask, close up of shirtless man with hat with 'ASS. Barber' written on upper arm, close up of man wearing eye patch holding hair shears, two shot of men smiling holding hair shears, man wearing head scarf, man talking into megaphone, Lowell Thomas talking to man with hat, three men talking, two men on boat, man in scuba uniform getting off of boat, satellite on ship, man sitting on ship looking through binoculars, men raising flag on staff, close up of man's bare torso, shot of men's arms showing tattoos, two men talking on boat; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2809)
    close up of native, close up of child, child holding onto back of boy, child looking up, palm trees, crowd on beach, landscape; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2810)
    tribal dancing, group outside under hut, tribal dance/ritual outside, two men in tribal sarongs, roosters walking on beach; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Fiji Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2811)
    men outside working on sculpture?, palm trees, men on tank, men snorkeling/diving, house on beach with satellite, man smoking pipe, men in front of tent, man on boat; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Danger Island, 1958; 322 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2812)
    Tribal boys chasing chicken. Adults place blood on boys along with crown of long leaves. Dancing ritual takes place. Boy blows into object. Boys swing from rope.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Black & White; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2813)
    Leaves, clapboard, man in striped jacket and tie, man pointing, something dark that has a light shining on it; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2814)
    Aerial view of ship in the water; men in a forest of palm trees, standing on a tank that says "USMC" and "3-H-1G" while working on some sort of pulley system; man operating a control system with a headpiece in; view from a ship; Navy helicopter landing on deck; people watching a ship sail away; small building with writing on it including: "October Eclipse," "Lowell Thomas" and "Best Wishes."; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2815)
    2 men talking, clapboard, count down clock, a key in a lock, man working with film, man wearing headset, a control board; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2816)
    Man sitting in a control room working at a desk; men standing outdoors at the top of stairs.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2817)
    Clouds; rockets set up; people on a ship; man holding an animal with a crowd of people behind him; he drinks out of a coconut; all the people sit at tables; women holding awnings above their heads while standing around a table where men are sitting.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Fiji Islands, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2818)
    Two men standing with two boys; two women standing together; helicopter flying and landed on island; military tank and various flags; aerial view of island; group of men on boat with one driving a forklift; another ship pulls up; man in captain hat talking to another man; view of men through circular windows.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Fiji Islands, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2819)
    Man with some kind of speaker behind him; men standing on deck of ship; big machine; people on the upper deck looking down; helicopters parked; multiple boats in the water; possibly film reels; man working with tools at a desk; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2820)
    man in a control room reading a book, writing something/measuring, clapboard, two men in the control room moving a table, measuring something across the table/showing blueprints or map, another man enters, control room of a ship possibly, men back at the table/blueprints/map, looking out the window, man in a floral shirt and cowboy hat, steering the ship, a rocket called "Sadie Thompson," men outside airbase next to the rocket, crane lifts the rocket and moves it, more cranes, men standing on platforms directing movements, helicopter landing, platform/crane, people continuing to help raise rocket and parts, people gathered on the deck of a ship, men taking pictures, men talking on the deck.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2821)
    metal structures with missiles? attached on ship, over the shoulder shot of men looking at missile, man opening up back of missile, shot looking down at man with missile, man moving object down with rope, man holding missile, close up of man, shot looking up at missile?, close up of dial, missiles on deck of ship, men looking out at water from ship; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2822)
    Man sitting in control room; look at a map; showing men through circular windows typical of a ship; view from boat with another boat approaching; men looking out from boat; landscape views.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2823)
    Ocean, men without shirts on the deck of a ship, moving equipment.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2824)
    men looking at other men in the far distance, people sitting in rows on the ground, people walking in the water, river, people trudging thought the river towards a house on the shore, people putting up a rope across the river, people reaching the shore of the river near the house, people holding up a net in the river, people holding fronds in the river, people dancing in between columns, people in a meditation-like stance, people standing in a huge group, net chatching a fish, people picking stuff up out of the water, a huge group of people standing by the shore, palm trees; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2825)
    men by a bunch of machinery, palm trees reflecting in the water by a building, huge group of palm trees, aerial view of buildings and palm trees, aerial view of layout of buildings, man using a machine, land and water, huge ship with equipment on it, ship sailing away, men working on the ship, man flying a helicopter; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2826)
    a ship docked, man leaning over ship railing, pile of materials, woman using audio equipment, men dancing in sarongs, group of people watching the men dance in front of palm trees; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2827)
    Landscapes; machine; ship sailing; helicopter and rockets on-board ship; men in cabin of ship operating controls; map of the Pacific Ocean from The National Geographic Magazine; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2828)
    tribal people outside of a hut, some on ladders fixing the straw roof, row boat on the beach, building hut again, people running from hut to the boat, girl leaning something against the boat, frames switching back and forth between the hut and the boat, group of people under the pavilion with a straw roof, a few men walking towards the pavilion, carrying a ladder, climbing ladder to the roof of the pavilion, boat raised over the sand, people rowing in boats, man falls out of boat, more rowing in boats.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2829)
    clapboard, woman's feet and legs, native woman dancing, native man dancing, native men sitting on ground, Lowell Thomas? dancing in tribal outfit, woman sitting and writing in book, woman swaddling baby, close up of baby, woman weighing baby, close up of woman's face, close up of woman holding baby; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2830)
    Girls in skirts with flowers in their hair, one playing the ukulele, two men walk over and talk to them, close-up of woman with ukulele and man dressed as a sailor, singing together?, 2 girls in skirts and 2 marine guys, one marine guy looking at plants.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Fiji Islands, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2831)
    Various native men, women and children walking, sitting, and hanging out around their village. Some people gathered around playing guitars.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Fiji Islands, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2832)
    sailors steering ship, controls/equipment/machines, ocean, 3 men on deck, ocean, aerial view of ship sailing through ocean, men on the deck again, sky, zoom in of controls, different men walking through, captains talking, satellite, captains talking again, crew standing around, operational equipment of ship, man using binoculars, man wearing a headset looking at the control panel, button that says "count down," another that says "instrumentation," person pushes the button, person flips a switch that says "arm," "rocket armed," and "fire."; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Fiji Islands, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2833)
    Military tank possibly driving through shallow water onto the ship; people watching from the upper deck; machine that says "Type RM16 Oscilloscope"; man at a desk drawing something; men standing on stacks of something.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey-Danger Island-Blow Up-Under Water Shot, 1957; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2834)
    person scuba diving, oxygen tanks, person holding onto reef for support, paddling, 2 scuba divers, grabbing reef, inspecting parts of the reef, more swimming/descending, reef, scuba divers; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2835)
    green black and yellow buttons, 2 yellow and a red button, box-like object with dial and scale on it attached to box with the buttons, man standing next to pole that says "Sadie Thomps" and "Lee Miss Kim", 2 navy helicopters and 3 people on a boat, people getting out of navy helicopters, rocket?, person sitting on top of boat, man in helmet, 6 people standing around navy helicopter, large group of people sitting at tables, 4 people talking, people standing around trees, clapboard; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2836)
    Lowell Thomas leaving airplaine; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2837)
    a globe, a smaller version of the globe, zooming in on the globe, river running through land, close up of clapboard; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2838)
    clapboard, Lowell Thomas in suit standing in front of planet model?, close up of Lowell Thomas, 'Danger Island' written on clapboard; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Fiji Island, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2839)
    clapboard, man holding unidentified object at camp with American flag flying in background, men looking at man holding object, close up of man looking, palm trees and building control panel, work space, man working at work space; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey Danger Island, 1957; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2840)
    tribal statue, women on stage hula dancing, clapboard, man in suit and boa dancing in front of stage, men playing drums on stage, close up of women's feet dancing, woman putting lei on man, close up of hula dancer's face, close up of hula skirt; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative